Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin literary autograph collection, 1841-1993.
Rudin, Gail and Stephen autograph collection, 1841-1993
- Symons, Julian: Manuscript, notes and clippings., 1978 (Box 15)
  Original manuscript and research archive for "The Tell-Tale Heart - The Life and Work of Edgar Allan Poe".
  Rudin # B-138A
- Symons, Julian: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Kent., Jun. 3, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Tarkington, Booth: Autograph letter to Ed., No date (Box 5, Folder 34)
  Regarding incident with Ed and dog.
- Tarkington, Booth: Autograph letter to Mr. Williamson. Indianapolis, IN., Jan. 15, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  Regarding speed of writing.
- Tarkington, Booth: Autographed letter to Mr. Starrett. Kennebunkport, Maine., Oct. 21, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Explains why he had been reluctant to publish his play Beaucaire in England.
  Rudin # B-139
- Thackeray, William Makepeace: Autographed letter addressed to Dear Madame. Brompton., Jun. 2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  Advice to an aspiring writer.
  Rudin # B-140
- Thackeray, William Makepeace: Autograph note to My dear cousin. Kensington., May 19, 1849 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  Regarding signature.
- Thackeray, William Makepeace: Autograph letter to Mr. Hallam. Kensington., Sep. 26, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  Regarding invitation.
- Thackeray, William Makepeace: Autograph letter to Ticknor and Fields publishing firm. London., Jun. 25, 1853 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  Regarding publication of novel in serial form.
- Thomas, Dylan: Typed letter to Richard Church. Hants., Feb. 22, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  Regarding The Map of Love.
- Thomas, Dylan: Autograph letter to Sir. Wales., May 27, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  Regarding political affiliation and S.C.R.
- Thoreau, Henry David: Autograph manuscript, unsigned., No date (Box 5, Folder 41)
  Regarding woods near Hubbard's Grove.
- Thurber, James: Typed letter to Major Melvyn Berlind. Cornwall, CT., Jan. 25, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Thurber's response to an admirer. "The only thing I have in common with James Joyce is bad eyesight".
  Rudin # B-141
- Thurber, James: Typed letter to publisher. Hot Springs, VA., Dec. 7, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Tolkien, J.R.R.: Autograph letter to George Engel. Oxford., Oct. 25, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  Regarding debt to "agelong tradition", The Lord of the Rings, duties at Oxford.
- Tuttiett, Mary G.: Autographed letter. Newport I. Wight., Apr. 22, 1889 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Discusses writing. "Style is a gift, though like other gifts it can be improved".
  Rudin # B-142
- Untermeyer, Louis: Typed letter to Mr. Hartley. Newton, CT., Jul. 30, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Updike, John: Typed note to Richard S. Fetters. Ipswich, MA. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  Responds to a letter asking, "What does success means to me".
  Rudin # B-143
- Uris, Leon: Typed manuscript., No date (Box 5, Folder 45)
  Regarding qualities of a good writer.
- Van de Water, Frederic Franklin: Typed letter to Ernest Kroll. New York, NY., Feb. 26, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- van Vogt, A.E.: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Hollywood, CA., Jun. 15, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Vonnegut, Kurt: Typed letter to Byron Troyer. New York, NY., Sep. 6, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Regarding Vonnegut's education and success.
- Vonnegut, Kurt: Typed letter to Gary Grossman., Apr. 22, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Regarding attempts to stop smoking.
- Wallace, Irving: Typed letter to Robert Hudson., Nov. 5, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Responds to questions posed to him regarding his views on pornography and censorship.
  Rudin # B-144
- Warren, Robert Penn: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Fairfield, CT., Aug. 1, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Warren, Robert Penn: Typed letter to Mr. Wilder. Fairfield, CT., Oct. 8, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Discusses prayer in the schools and Faulkner.
  Rudin # B-145
- Waugh, Evelyn: Autograph letter to Alfred McIntyre. Stinchcombe., Oct. 8, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Regarding Brideshead Revisited.
- Webster, Noah: Autograph manuscript., No date (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Definitions.
- Wells, H.G.: Autograph letter to My dear Brown. Grasse., Feb. 4, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Regarding Query advertisement.
- Wells, H.G.: Autograph letter to a publisher. London., Dec. 4, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Regarding agreement for book.
- Wells, H.G.: Autograph letter to a publisher. London., Mar. 11, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Regarding Star-begotten.
- Wells, H.G.: Autograph letter to Viking Press. Grasse., Apr. 26, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Regarding The Brothers.
- Wheatley, Dennis: Autographed letter to Mr. Earle. London, England., 1933 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  Announcing the publication of his novel, "The Forbidden Territory".
  Rudin # B-146
- White, E.B.: Typed letter to Mr. Wells. New York., Nov. 3, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Discusses and defines his choice of using the word "Chinaman" instead of "Chinese" at the end of World War II.
  Rudin # B-147
- White, E.B.: Typed letter to Wayne Chatterton. North Brooklin, ME., Sep. 27, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  A lengthy discussion of the famous New Yorker "profiles" and an unflattering "profile" of his colleague, Alexander Woollcott.
  Rudin # B-148
- White, E.B.: Typed letter to Charles L. Baldwin. North Brooklin, ME., Nov. 24, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Regarding split infinitives, the day's youth.
- Whitman, Walt: Autograph letter to Talcott Williams. Camden, NJ., Dec. 14, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Whittier, John Greenleaf: Autograph letter to Dear Friend. Danvers., Jan. 2, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Regarding W.C. Bryant. With photo.
- Wilbur, Richard: Autographed letter to Mr. Cary. Wesleyan University, Middletown, CT., Aug. 5, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Discusses the process of revision. "The point is that the smallest word counts".
  Rudin # B-149
- Wilde, Oscar: Autograph letter to Mrs. Gielgud. Chelsea., c. July 1881 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Regarding invitation. With photos.
- Wilder, Thorton: Autographed letters to James Thomson. Florence. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Manuscript with cover letter. Wilder defends the Silent Generation, predicting how it will affect America's future.
  Rudin # B-150
- Wilder, Thorton: Autographed letter to Jay L. Bradley. Capri., Oct. 28, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Discusses the pursuit of a career in writing and the pros and cons of attending college.
  Rudin # B-151
- Wilder, Thornton: Autograph letter to Pearl Buck. Hollywood, CA., Jul. 14, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Regarding Our Town.
- Wilder, Thorton: Autographed postcard to Harry Thornton Moore. Hamden 17, CT., Oct. 28, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  "Imaginative narration is a very stern mistress; she wants no other gods but herself".
  Rudin # B-152
- Wilder, Thornton: Autograph letters to Miriam Benkovitz. Hamden, CT., May 29, 1969; May 5, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Regarding discussions of Wilder; Memory of Ellen Hayes.
- Wilder, Thornton: Autograph letter to Joseph Blotner. Edgartown, MA., Jul. 17, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Regarding William Faulkner. With Wilder stamps and envelope.
- Wilder, Thorton: Autographed letters to Dalma Brunauer. Hamden, CT., 1974, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  Letter 12/9/1974 - Thanking her for her thoughtful essay on ""Bridge of San Luis Rey"" and remarking that many are angry that he does not more strongly affirm Christian doctrine. Letter 11/11/1975 - Discusses how his Protestant upbringing relates to ""Bridge of San Luis Rey"". (With unrelated Willa Cather envelope signed and addressed to Wilder)
  Rudin # B-153
- Williams, Tennessee: Typed letter to John Hunter. Key West, FL., Feb. 3, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Regarding article for Yale Magazine on Dylan Thomas. With magazine and photo.
- Williams, Tennessee :Typed letter to Audrey, Nov. 7, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  "America is very cruel to its artists who have had reversals of fortune."
  Rudin # B-154
- Williams, Tennessee: Typed letter to Tim Moore. San Francisco, CA., Aug. 14, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  Writing to a potential "traveling companion", Williams mentions that "I never fall out of love, which makes it a sad sort of poem".
  Rudin # B-155
- Williams, William Carlos: Typed letter to Arioste Lonchard. Rutherford, NJ., Nov. 6, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  A letter on Williams' feelings for Ezra Pound. In a presentation portfolio.
  Rudin # B-156
- Williams, William Carlos: Typed letter addressed to Dear Uhlman. Rutherford, NJ., May 29, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  "The structure of the poem must be changed and not merely must it speak about new things".
  Rudin # B-157
- Williams, William Carlos: Autographed manuscript. Rutherford, NJ., Aug. 17, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  A tribute to the great American photographer, Alfred Eisenstadt.
  Rudin # B-158
- Wilson, Edmund: Autographed letter addressed to Dear Hazel. Red Bank, NJ., Nov. 12, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  A long chatty letter referring to his work and to his reading. Thinks New York is an awful place to live and coments, "I haven't met an intelligent clergyman…since I have been here."
  Rudin # B-159
- Winslow, Elizabeth: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley., Mar. 7, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 20A)
- Wodehouse, P.G.: Typed letter to Alec Waugh. Long Island, NY., Jan. 4, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Regarding recent knighthood.
- Wolfe, Thomas: Typed letter to Du Bose Heyward. Brooklyn, NY., Sep. 8, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Regarding NY summer, invitation to Charleston.
- Woolf, Virginia: Autograph letter to Logan Pearsall Smith. Tavistock Square., Dec. 4, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  Regarding love.
- Wordsworth, William: Autograph letter to Edward Quillinan., Apr. 8, 1841 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Regarding daughter's upcoming marriage to Quillinan.
- Wouk, Herman: Typed letter to Matthew Held. Washington D.C., Apr. 28, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  Regarding Karl Popper.
- Wright, Richard: Typed letter to Miss Pergament. NY., Sep. 10, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  He critiques a story sent to him by his correspondent for review.
  Rudin # B-160
- Zaturenska, Marya: Autographed letter to Wesley Hartley. NY, Apr. 6, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 22)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books
Victory, Joseph Conrad. Critique in the front written by Pearl Buck. Rudin # B-18.
The Four Seasons of Success, by Budd Schulberg. Signed by the author.
Giovanni's Room, by James Baldwin. Unsigned. See Box 7, Folder 8.
Bernard Shaw: His Life and Personality, by Hesketh Pearson. Including notes, signatures, and newspaper clippings on Shaw.